RG 059, Advisory Committee on Fuel
Connecticut State Library
Advisory Committee on Fuel records
1947-1948
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Advisory Committee on Fuel
1 cubic foot
The Advisory Committee on Fuel was formed by Governor McConaughy in 1947, to come up with solutions for the possible severe fuel oil shortage during the coming winter.
RG059
T002727
Historical Note
In November 1947, members of the petroleum industry in Connecticut believed there was a danger of a severe fuel oil shortage during the coming winter. Per their request, Governor McConaughy appointed ten industry representatives to an Advisory Committee on Fuel. The Committee met on December 3, 1947, under the chairmanship of C.N. Mitchell, and Leo A. Hibson shortly became the paid Executive Secretary. The Committee met frequently, with headquarters at three successive locations in Hartford, and worked to establish cooperative agreements between members to facilitate supply and transportation of oil into the state, assist small and unequipped dealers whose supply was threatened, organize local committees to deal with emergency situations, set aside standing supplies for emergency distribution under the Governor's control, borrow oil from the United States Navy, and allocate for distribution the supplies that were received. In the spring, the crisis appeared to be over and the Committee concluded its work in March 1948.
Scope and Content
Records include the Committee’s report to the Governor, correspondence, workbooks, and subject files.
Related Material
RG 005:030, James L. McConaughy and James C. Shannon gubernatorial records.
The following folders are in Box 502:
Fuel Advisory committee - Minutes of Meetings
Fuel - Correspondence with: Mayors, First Selectmen Re: Fuel Committees' Conservation
Fuel - Correspondence with Newspapers Re: Governor's speech on Fuel, 1/5/1948. Also copy of speech.
Fuel - Correspondence with Oil Companies Re: Fuel Supplies & Reservation of Heating Fuels
Fuel - Correspondence with President, Secretary of Commerce, Navy Department, Department of Interior, Maritime Commission, and Congressional delegates
The following folders are in Box 503:
Fuel - General File
Fuel - Reports from State Department Re: Conservation Of Fuel
Fuel - Texas Oil Strike Correspondence with President, Congressional Delegates, American Oil Company, And Governor Robert Bradford [MA]
RG 050, War Council, 1940-1945, (see especially the Fuel Section file, which includes papers of the Fuel Adminstrator).
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Advisory Committee on Fuel
Persons:
Mitchell, C.N.; Hibson, Leo A.
Subjects:
Connecticut. Advisory Committee on Fuel -- Records and correspondence; Fuel -- Conservation -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Correspondence; Worksheets; Reports
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1947-1948
  - 1. Report to Governor, 1947-1948; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Mimeographed report with exhibits (incomplete).
  - 2. General file, 1947-1948 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, reports, memoranda, etc.
    Arranged by subject or correspondent.
    - Advisory Committee (Box 1)
    - Contributions (Box 1)
    - District Chairmen (Box 1)
    - District #1 (J.G. Gleason, Chairman) (Box 1)
    - District #2 (M.J. Hoffman, Chairman) (Box 1)
    - District #3 (E.W. Van Deventer, Chairman) (Box 1)
    - District #4 (W.E. Wesson, Chairman) (Box 1)
    - District #5 (C.A. Patterson, Chairman) (Box 1)
    - District #6 (E. L. Lord [or O.L. Lord], Chairman) (Box 1)
    - District #7 (B.H. Van Mater, Chairman) (Box 1)
    - District #8 (Charles Bedient, Chairman) (Box 1)
    - District #9 (C.E. Small, Chairman) (Box 1)
    - District #10 (G.H. Stetson, Chairman) (Box 1)
    - District #11 (W.D. Roth, Chairman) (Box 1)
    - Lists (Box 1)
    - Local Committee Members (Box 1)
    - Special Navy Diesel Fuel, Special (Box 1)
    - Navy Oil (Box 1)
    - Navy Oil-Releases (Box 1)
    - Shipments of Anthracite to Connecticut (Box 1)
    - State Police Reports (Box 1)
  - 3. Correspondence file, 1947-1948 (Box 1)
    Incoming and outgoing letters.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - 4. Workbooks, 1947-1948; 2 looseleaf binders (Box 1)
    Contains notes, lists and worksheets of various kinds - evidently records of fuel on hand, received, transferred, etc. by oil companies in Connecticut.